ZIKANG (KHAN) ZHENG

Singapore|Beijing, China ♦ (+65)9376-1147 ♦ zikangzheng@gmail.com/e1323314@u.nus.edu

Professional Summary

Strong interest in product management particularly in corporations strategy in the innovation guiding teams and addressing market user needs. About 3 years of experience in Al/Finance/Consulting companies involving product management, full-stack coding, UI/UX and Business/data analytic. Previous experience in strategy regarding new features in artificial intelligence chatbot, and another in developing the Finance system in the University housing & finance system.

Strength: Enthusiastic, Self-Driven, Deep Thinking, Responsible, Positive, Independent, Fast Learner, Plan Ahead

CORE COMPETENCE

- Programming (Python, PHP, React, Jquery, C++, C, R & Java)
- DataBase (Oracle, MySQL, PL/SQL)
- Data Analysis (Excel, Matlab, SSRS)
- Data Visualization

- Product & Prototype Design (Adobe CC, Figma, XD, Miro)
- Modeling (Sketchup, Fusion, AutoCAD)
- Game Development (Unity)
- Design Thinking

- Team Management & Leadership
- Entrepreneurship Strategy
- Product Ownership
- Pitching & Problem Solving
- Communication & Responsibility

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Engineer Design and Innovation National University of Singapore - Singapore

• Relevant Courses: Entrepreneurship Strategy, Venture Capital Funding, Design Strategies & Leadership, Design Thinking & Product Development, Creativity & Problem-Solving.

Bachelor of Science: Mathematical Science

07/2016 - 05/2021

01/2024 - 12/2024

University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

- Academic Accolades: Outstanding International Student, Go Global Structured Undergraduate Research
- Relevant Courses: Computer Graphics, Digital Media Design, SQL Databases, Human Computer Interaction, Machine Learning & Data Mining, Computer Hardware & Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence.

Professional Experience

AIGC Product manager Intern Jieyue Xingchen – Beijing, China

11/2023 - 01/2024

- Led a team of 30 employees in creating the AI risk management platform. Power them by product management process thinking. Successfully launched in the Chinese market and enhanced the AI social responsibility.
- Managed UX researcher, marketing specialist, and programming team. Resolve team conflict via win-win strategy in decision-making. Well produced ahead of the OKR and Increased 40% number of the target users.
- Conducted marketing & social media search, app store search, and competitor analysis. Generated a report regarding business strategy & product insights.
- Conceptualised a distinctive storytelling product strategy that highlights unique features within the Large Language Model market. Enable the company to win in the large language model area by product strategy.
- Hosted the user interview involving listening, understanding, asking following questions, and identifying the target user needs, insights, behaviours and their demands in LLM and produced a solid user product experience.

The University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

 Intern
 01/2020 - 08/2020

 Part Time
 09/2020 - 07/2021

 Program analyst Full Time
 08/2021 - 08/2023

- Developed and launched integrated systems for food, finances, and housing systems using JQuery and PHP in Yii Framework. Increased operational efficiency and improved satisfaction for over 55,000 students and staff.
- Orchestrated the UI/UX design using Adobe Photoshop and Figma and enhanced product adoption rates.
- Programmed a robust PL/SQL to manage Oracle database by building schema views, packages and Oracle form builder. Optimised database performance, significantly reducing data retrieval times and increasing reliability.
- Designed and Developed SQL to automate the calculation of SSRS reports. Enhanced and Speed up decision-making.

Planned and Designed the system-level testing and covered 100+ cases in different user scenarios.

IT Department Intern

09/2019 - 12/2019

Pythian - Ottawa, Canada

- Established hardware and software support using customer ticketing systems including JIRA, JIRA Service Desk and Slack to end-users, and achieved a consistent track record of high user satisfaction, and managed the customer issue support listening to their pain points and understanding their urgency.
- Crafted and deployed the company's internal website utilising Confluence, JavaScript, HTML and CSS for
 optimal functionality and user engagement and workflow processes, enhancing operational efficiency within
 the company.

RESEARCH & PROJECT

Project Happraisal | UBC SPIN Lab

03/2023 - 09/2023

- Conducted research on haptic technology and emotional release therapy. Collaborated with a HCI team in Stanford. Conducted haptic research reading paper and planning for the next development procedures.
- Designed Figma prototype for the WearOS application interface, and designed IOT robot prototype.
 Implemented Python Websocket server and data processing and data mining.
- Developed an Arduino ESP32 robot via Arduino IDE, and analysed healthcare data to accurately detect emotions, enhancing patient care.

Visual Graph Comparison | Supervisor: Professor Kuijper

05/2019 - 12/2019

- Conducted research into factors influencing perception of differences between graphs; used screen-capturing technologies and thinking-aloud protocols paired with qualitative content analysis to identify several contributing factors including edge crossings, shape and symmetry based on research participant observations.
- Analysed participants' comments and identified methods to improve research methodologies; determined 8
 influencing factors of graphical perception.

Third Person game COVID-Omega | BC Game Jam 2022 (MAP, Audio/SFX & UI Developer)

09/2022

- Collaborated with a team of 7 participants to ideate, develop and launch pandemic-style game titled
 Covid-Omega. Fostered a dynamic team environment and enhanced digital entertainment during the pandemic.
- Produced Unity and Unreal Engine to design game map and user interface; employed SFX for audio implementation and developed C# scripts for the game's blueprint with a robust and intuitive interface and great gaming experience.
- Project Link: https://ventOs.itch.io/covid-omega

CERTIFICATIONS

Google UX Design Professional Certificate | Google

Business Strategy Specialization Certificate | University of Virginia

Introduction to Marketing Certificate | Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania

Successful Negotiation: Essential Strategies & Skills Certificate | University of Michigan

Conflict Management Specialization Certificate | University of California, Irvine

Green Economy & Trade Certificate | UN Institute for Training & Research & Partnership for Action on Green Economy

The Materiality of ESG Factors Certificate | Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania

Introduction to Psychology Certificate | *Yale University*

INTERESTS & LINKS

Interests | Kyudo (Japanese Archery), Photography
GitHub Link | github.com/khan123451 | Personal Portfolio | www.khanzheng.com